ALEX PETROV

Location: Vinnytsia, Ukraine

Phone:

+38 (067) 421 5180

Email:

alexpetrov0895@gmail.com

Summary

Motivated and creative front-end developer with analytical thinking to cope with different challenges in development. Strong written and verbal English (C1) and good communication skills for effective dialogue with colleagues. Able to monitor own work and learn new web technologies within short time horizons. Collaborate in a team effectively. A responsible and self-reliant person.

Web Development Skills

- Advanced knowledge of HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Commercial experience in Vue.JS framework, Vuex and ES6
- Good command of Responsive Design, SCSS, SASS, and Bootstrap
- Practical use of Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, XD and Figma
- Basic knowledge of Node.JS and React
- Familiar with JQuery
- Good understanding of Git

Work Experience

Front-End Developer - May 2021 - Current Viseven, UA

- Wrote efficient and maintainable HTML/CSS/JavaScript code using Vue.JS
- Created user-friendly web slides, single page applications and web pages for medical institutions and their products
- Maintained and improved projects codebase
- Reviewed code and fixed bugs in existing projects

QA Research Analyst/Front-End Developer – April 2019 – May 2021 **Ciklum**, UA

- Performed valid and accurate product research for Staples US.
- Gathered, arranged and corrected research data to create representative product description.
- Conducted product data analysis, checked information accuracy and integrity.
- As a freelancer created web pages and applications with a big focus on markup languages like HTML5, also CSS3 and JavaScript

Education

Master of Education: **Applied Linguistics** – 2017 - 2018

University of Bedfordshire, United Kingdom

Master of Education: **English Language** – 2016 - 2018 **Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv**, Ukraine

Bachelor of Arts: History - 2012 - 2016

Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, Ukraine

Languages

- English C1
- Polish B1
- Russian C2
- German A2
- Ukrainian native

Contacts

• Email: alexpetrov0895@gmail.com

• **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-petrov-3911361a8

• **GitHub**: https://github.com/alpet95

• **Portfolio website**: https://alexpetrov.netlify.app

Additional Information

- Married
- Hobbies: play the musical instruments, learn foreign languages, cinema, travels